Phoenix Book Shop mss., 1951-1989 LMC 1992
Lilly Library
Phoenix Book Shop mss.
1951-1989
Lilly Library
Phoenix Book Shop
LMC 1992
1 folio oversize
56 Boxes
The Phoenix Book Shop mss., 1951-1989, are the papers of the Phoenix Book Shop located first at 18 Cornelia Street, then at 22 Jones Street in New York City, and operated by Robert Alfred Jump Wilson, 1922-, bibliographer and bookseller.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Independent bookstore located first at 18 Cornelia Street, then at 22 Jones Street in New York City, and operated by Robert Alfred Jump Wilson, 1922-, bibliographer and bookseller.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: Correspondence; Customer orders (general); Customer orders (standing), 1964-1987; Invoices sent (general); Purchase orders; Paid bills; Additions.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains correspondence, standing orders, miscellaneous orders, invoices sent, and Phoenix Book Shop orders, paid bills, and account ledgers. Also included in the files are a few manuscripts Wilson considered for publication, galleys for some Phoenix Book Shop publications, and documents and memorabilia relating to the history of the shop.
Acquisition Information
Acquired 1974-1989
Booksellers and bookselling --United States; Independent bookstores --United States; Booksellers and bookselling; Wilson, Robert A. (Robert Alfred), 1922-; Wilson, Robert A. (Robert Alfred), 1922- --Correspondence.; Phoenix Book Shop.
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  Arrangement
  Arranged as received, either chronologically or alphabetically within a year.
  - 1929 - 1966, Feb. (Box 1)
  - 1966, Mar. - 1967, Sept. (Box 2)
  - 1967, Oct. - 1969, Apr. (Box 3)
  - 1969, May - Dec. (Box 4)
  - 1970 - 1971, Mar. (Box 5)
  - 1971, Apr. - 1972, June (Box 6)
  - 1972, July - 1973, Sept. (Box 7)
  - 1973, Oct. - 1974, Dec. (Box 8)
  - 1974 (A-Z) - 1975, Dec. (Box 9)
  - 1976, Jan. - 1977, Feb., 1977, Mar.-Dec. (A-H) (Box 10)
  - 1977, Mar.-Dec. (F-Z) - 1978 (A-H) (Box 11)
  - 1978 (H-Z) - 1979 (A-L) (Box 12)
  - 1979 (M-Z) - 1980 (A-N) (Box 13)
- Customer orders (general) (Box 14)
  Arranged chronologically
  - 1962 - 1964 (Box 14)
  - 1965 - 1968, Apr. (Box 15)
  - 1968, May - 1969, Aug. (Box 16)
  - university orders, 1969, Sept. - 1972, Feb.; 1973, Nov.; 1967-1970 (Box 17)
  - 1974 - 1976 (Box 18)
  - 1977 - 1979 (Box 19)
  - 1980 - 1983 (Box 20)
- Customer orders (standing), 1964-1987 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, orders, and invoices for the following institutions: (Box 21)
    - Huntington Library, 1962-1974 (Box 21)
    - Indiana University, 1964-1983 (Box 21)
    - Michigan State University, 1968-1982 (Box 21)
    - New York Public Library, 1970-1978 (Box 21)
    - New York University, 1964-1971 (Box 21)
    - Northwestern University, 1969-1982 (Box 21)
    - State University of New York at Buffalo, 1964-1974 (Box 21)
    - Syracuse University, 1966-1976 (Box 21)
    - Temple University, 1968-1970 (Box 21)
    - University of California, Davis, 1966-1977 (Box 21)
    - UCLA, 1966-1987 (Box 21)
    - UC, San Diego, 1968-1974 (Box 21)
    - UC, Santa Cruz, 1968-1975 (Box 21)
    - University Louisville, 1966-1971 (Box 21)
    - University of Nevada, Reno, 1963-1984 (Box 21)
    - University of North Carolina, 1968-1974 (Box 21)
    - West Virginia University, 1968-1970 (Box 21)
    - Yale University, 1971-1984 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, orders,...cont. (Box 22)
- Invoices sent (general) (Box 23)
  - 1962, Mar. - 1965, Mar. (Box 23)
  - 1965, Apr. - 1967, Oct. (Box 24)
  - 1967, Nov. - 1969 (Box 25)
  - 1970 - 1972 (Box 26)
  - 1973 - 1975 (Box 27)
  - 1976 - 1978, Mar. (Box 28)
  - 1978, Apr. - 1980, Apr. (Box 29)
  - 1980, May - 1982, July (Box 30)
- Purchase orders (Box 31)
  - 1969 - 1977 (Box 31)
  - 1978 - 1983, May (Box 32)
- Paid bills (Box 33)
  Arranged as received, either chronologically or alphabetically within a year
  - 1962 - 1965 (Box 33)
  - 1966 - 1967/68 (A-S) (Box 34)
  - 1967/68 (T-Z) - 1971/72 (A-D) (Box 35)
  - 1971/72 (E-Z) - 1974/75 (A-H) (Box 36)
  - 1974/75 (I-Z) - 1976/77 (Box 37)
  - 1978/79 - 1979 (Box 38)
  - 1980, July - 1983 (A-M) (Box 39)
- Additions (Box 40)
  Mostly unarranged
  - Customer invoices:, 1985, Sept. - 1989, Jan. (Box 40)
  - Kerouac bibliography photo page (Box 40)
  - Customer ledger accounts:, 1976 - 1983 (Box 40)
  - Accounts received:, 1962 - 1989 (Box 40)
  - Correspondence:, 1982 -1989 (Box 40)
  - Snyder bibliography, Part 1 - Original camera-ready copy (Box 40)
  - Paid bills:, 1988 - 1989 (Box 40)
  - Ledger books, (7 volumes) (Box 40)
  - Correspondence:, 1980 (O-Z) - 1981 (Box 41)
  - Correspondence:, 1981/82 - 1983 (A-D) (Box 42)
  - Correspondence:, 1983 (E-P); 1984/85 (O-Z) (Box 43)
  - Paid bills:, 1983 (N-Z) - 1984 (Box 43)
  - Accounts received:, 1973-1981 (Box 43)
  - Ledgers, (8 volumes) (Box 43)
  - Customer invoices:, 1982, Aug. - 1985, Aug. (Box 44)
  - Customer orders:, 1984 - 1988 (Box 45)
  - Customer invoices:, 1987, Aug. - 1988, Aug. (Box 46)
  - Accounts receivable (Box 46)
  - Account statement:, 1987, Jan. - 1988, Aug. (Box 46)
  - Ledgers, 1962-1978 (Box 47)
  - Accounts receivable, 1960s(?)-1983 (Box 47)
  - Correspondenceand, 1988-1989; undated (Box 48)
  - Printed (Box 48)
  - Invoices (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: manuscripts for 49 Phoenix Book Shop publications, collection appraisals made by Wilson, and materials relating to history of the shop - original lease, photos, shop sign design, etc.
  - Miscellaneous, cont. (Box 50)
  - Paid bills, 1988 (Box 51)
  - Invoices, 1986-1987 (Box 52)
  - Purchase orders (Box 52)
  - Publishers, 1982-1988 (Box 52)
  - Gertrude Stein bibliography (Box 52)
  - Gary Snyder bibliography (Box 53)
  - Financial (Box 53)
  - Correspondence:, 1954; 1986-1988 (Box 53)
  - Photographs (Box 53)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1988 (Box 54)
  - Finances (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 55)
  - Mock-up for Bibliography of Charles Olson (Box 56)
  - Drawing of cat, Ephemeron, by Carl Ashby (Ovflat 4)